# **ROOPA L UPPAR**

## React.js Developer

Contact: 9380683319 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/roopa-uppar-1901141b3/

**Online Profiles:** 

E-mail: roopauppar80@gmail.com Github: <a href="https://github.com/Roopauppar">https://github.com/Roopauppar</a>

Location: Bangalore, Karnataka India Portfolio: <a href="https://roopauppar.github.io/portfolio/">https://roopauppar.github.io/portfolio/</a>

#### **CAREER OBJECTIVES**

Associate Software Engineer with 1.5 years of experience, I am looking forward to a challenging position in a dynamic organisation to utilize my knowledge and skills, while making a significant contribution to the success of company.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

May 2023-Oct 2023

# Elena Geo Systems Pvt Ltd, Bangalore Junior Software Developer

- Worked on Elena Main Site (Company website)
- Built buoy Monitoring system to keep live track of 22 buoys based on light, location and battery.
- Integrated a React Leaflet map to visualise the real-time positions of the buoys on the map.
- Implemented Chart.js to display the overall status of all buoys and implemented service worker for low battery notifications related to the buoys.
- Built a stable and maintainable code base using React JS.
- Designed Frontend code using HTML, CSS, Javascript to create responsive web application.

Nov 2021- Nov 2022

# Infynow Software Solutions LLP, Belagavi

#### **Associate Software Engineer**

- Worked on Client and Company Project
- Implemented designs using HTML,CSS,Bootstrap,JavaScript,React.js
- Have worked with web debugging tools (Chrome developer console)
- Developed responsive web applications to provide an optimal viewing experience across a wide range of devices, from desktops to smartphones.
- Conducted Performance optimization to enhance the speed of web applications.
- Performed bug fixes and code reviews

## **EDUCATION**

BCA Rani Channamma University, Belagavi
2017-2020 Bharatesh College of Computer Applications, Belagavi

72.92%

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript
- Bootstrap
- Json
- React.js
- Tailwind CSS
- Basic Knowledge About Git and GitHub

## PERSONAL PROJECTS

# **Expense Tracker**

## https://github.com/Roopauppar/expensetracker

- Built a speech recognition-based expense tracker using React and Speechly API.
- Created a visual dashboard using ChartJS to perform the analytics and display the transactions.
- Implemented ContextAPI and localStorage to store and keep track of the transactions.
- Deployed the application in GitHub.

#### **E-commerce Website**

## https://github.com/Roopauppar/my-mobile

- Built an E-commerce website using React
- Implemented Redux to keep track of the application.
- Deployed the application in GitHub.

## **CERTIFICATES**

**React.js** Besant Technologies, Rajajinagar Bangalore

## **INTERNSHIP & TRAINING**

Aug-Oct 2021

## Web Development Intern, Vritika Infotech, Belagavi

- Worked on Web Technology of the Company Projects
- Worked on Manual Testing and SEO(Search Engine Optimization)